Got a couple more people joining in right now.
Super excited. What's up, Ryan? Can you hear me?
Sure can hear Me. Yes, sir.
It's good to hear you. It's been a minute.
I know, man. I, it's been busy,
but I'm really looking forward to plugging back in with you
and, um, getting active again and stuff.
So it's been, it's been busy,
but it's time to, to retool the tools
of the trade, so to speak.
Retool the tools. Sharpen the saw. Yeah.
Gotta put the metal pedal to the metal. Gotta, yeah,
A little going bit of swinging, a little bit
of swinging ax manually stuffs back, back to sharpen.
Yeah. All of the things, all of the idioms.
Um, are you, uh, how, how are things going on your end?
Are you, have you launched any ads?
Well, so created now three different digital
course offerings.
Um, and so a lot of that was kind of plugging away on,
on the course video content website and all that.
And so now, kind of to the point of what I just said,
coming back to like, okay, it's time to be, to be an ad guy.
Nice. Um, but yeah, so ads and, um,
and funnels are kind of like,
it's on the agenda at, at scale.
Love it. I think. Yeah.
It's like you have to put on different hats depending on
if you're building a brand new business, it's like,
all right, I gotta create the product now.
I've done that. Now I gotta put all the automations
together, then I gotta create the ads,
then I gotta do customer service.
You know, it's just this linear approach.
But, um, tell me more about, like, where you're at
with the business or like in terms of your ad strategy.
Do you have one?
No, I mean, to be honest, I said I,
I probably wear too many hats
and I'm, I'm trying to figure out how to scale
and sort of, uh, outsource and,
or sort of, uh, really well outsource.
Yeah. So, um, I've been a little bit too much of a website
and digital course building guy,
and I really want to kind of, to be honest,
more focused on becoming an ad and funnel guy.
And so I'm, I'm a little bit green in that area, right?
So that's really why I'm here.
It's what, why, how I found you in the first place.
Well, that's perfect, man.
I think the beauty is no matter who you are, where you are,
what's your expertise?
Like, you can be an ad guy, I think, uh,
it's just like learning your ABCs.
It's, uh, it's just starting, like knowing
that you have the letter A to start with
and you just progressively learn all the, the letters.
I think the hardest part is like, you jump into it
and you get lost because you don't have a structure
Yeah. To follow,
right. Just like with anything.
Um, so I'm definitely down to talk about
that, to help you out.
And I think it'll help out a lot of people
who are on the call, because I think one of the key things
In getting to becoming an ad guy is really understanding,
like market research, angle research, customer avatar,
research, um, defining your message, your messaging,
because that is the fundamental to
really developing the ads.
Like the ads will come after.
Once you've developed that, once you are very clear on your
audience, your messaging, your angle,
and your offer, then the ads part really becomes
easy, in my opinion.
So. Awesome, man.
We got, um, John, it's good to see you, brother.
Thanks for always, uh, being a late night editor on calls.
Um, sweet man.
But yeah, I would love to make,
can you share a little bit more about your, your training,
and then maybe I can walk you through a little bit of
that ad research process?
Yeah, there's slightly related,
actually the two core ones,
but, um, fundamentally there's a solar company
that is trying to branch out and create new dealers.
And so they're basically, it's like a comprehensive training
for, largely for roofing contractors,
but anyone try to start a solar sales company
or expand their current company to kind
of accommodate solar sales.
Mm-Hmm. So the training is very much like, uh,
you own a business and you wanna become a solar business,
um, or really you're kind of a salesman
and you wanna sell solar.
And the other one is in the real estate space, um, kind
of host, manager, realtor, everything
around investment properties, how to kind of get up
and running, particularly with an Airbnb focus.
So both of those are fairly saturated areas.
So it's, it's not a secret that it's like a lot
of people are trying to push, um, Airbnb, uh,
training material and, and to some degree solar as well.
Yeah. Um, so yeah, they, the,
I think the Airbnb one probably is really saturated,
the solar one, probably less so.
And I think even less so the idea of like, Hey, you, this is
how you kinda launch a business in a box
to become a solar sales company.
So, but yeah, that,
those are my two core ones, I would say for now.
Got it. Got it. Yeah, those are definitely like,
I would say, very saturated, but, um,
Yeah, for sure.
The, the content is great, though.
The course teachers are really like market
leaders in their space.
Um, and they're, so, they're definitely, I mean,
I, I guess I do pride myself.
I, I'm pretty good at putting together courses.
Like I said, I'm not, I'm trying to become an ad guy now,
and I definitely bit off more than I can chew early thinking
that I could learn it quickly.
And it's like, okay, this is really hard to get good fast,
which I should have appreciated from the start,
but it's definitely, uh, a
Challenge. Yeah. So, so, you
know,
you know the niche pretty well, would you say?
I do now, um, those two niches? Yeah, I do now.
Um, so I don't know the niches super well.
I've done like, solar stuff in the past,
like I've done solar ads, um,
but I've also seen a bunch of solar ads.
Um, I guess it, it, it,
it requires just be a better understanding of, um,
like what is your offer?
Do you know? Is it clear?
Yeah, well, so the offer for the solar aspect is,
is essentially like become a solar business,
like solar business in a box.
Okay. Launch scale
and grow a solar company from, from scratch.
Okay. And so it's largely for businesses that are sort
of already selling ancillary services.
So the idea is like, you're a roofing company,
you sell hvac, like you're already at the kitchen table
with, you know, mom and dad or whatever, uh, homeowner.
And it's like, Hey, if you're already repairing their roof,
like throw solar on or you're already repairing hvac, like,
and so then, but the real hook in this is we teach you how,
and then we, if you want,
you can just come under our umbrella.
It's almost like a, a franchise structure,
but it's like you can pretty much become a dealer of us
and you get access to all of our tools,
resources on top of training.
So I would say it's sort
of like become a solar business in 30 days type thing,
where it's, 'cause we train you to do it,
but you can become a dealer.
So that's kind of the, the ultimate offer, I guess.
Okay. That makes a little bit more sense.
So just essentially people
who are already running these types of services
who wanna expand their service line, um,
to obviously generate more revenue
For their business. Yeah. And especially
in, into like, what I think a lot
of companies that are like really good at, like, anyways,
that's, that's pretty much the, yeah, the summary.
Summary. Got it. Um, have you heard
of a tool called bsl.ai?
I, it sounds very familiar. Haven't used it.
Okay. So I'm gonna show you right now, I'm gonna, um,
share my screen and
because I don't know the niche super well, um, I want
to kind of just like run through this,
uh, exercise with you.
Uh, do you mind sharing your
website with me, if that's okay?
Yeah, there's, uh, selling solar.com is,
and it's a little bit MVP right now, a lot more, um,
features to add to it, but pretty good idea right now.
Okay. Very cool. So here's what I'm gonna do.
So, vsl.ai, it's a great automation AI tool.
Uh, I use it all the time in my agency to basically do a lot
of customer research, um,
pain points, all that kind of stuff. Well, it's,
It's kind of funny, just today I was like, spent an hour
and a half putting together my, I mean, there's
so many trying to really kind of build a tech stack that is,
there's so many options now in the AI space.
It's like half half of my day is spent towards like, trying
to source, test out different, like, tools
and figure out which ones work.
So it's funny how I'd actually love to do that.
I almost would love to start like a complimentary service
or, I mean, and a lot of folks do this,
but finding the tools to use like in, in quick order is, um,
is always half the, the battle.
Yeah, you can, it's easy to get lost in the sauce
with a lot of the apps.
Like, um, so I don't know.
For me, my workflow is like starting here.
'cause like the, the research is everything.
Um, but I'll, let me just walk you through
and then for anybody in the, in the call right now,
if you want to drop your questions in here so I can get back
to them while I do this demonstration, um, I'll make sure
to answer any of your questions.
So, uh, via sell.ai, um, I link this in the course,
so if you wanted to, you know, get this, um, you can.
But, so basically from here,
you create your own product or your offer.
Um, so let's say, for example, let's create yours. Okay.
Uh, yours is called selling solar, right? Yep.
Selling solar. Sounds like selling sunset,
like the, uh, the show.
Exactly. Since I don't know too much, I don't have
as much information on this.
I'm just taking the copy from your site.
I'm just gonna Yeah, just basically drop it in here.
Um, and I'm sure there's a lot more content that
we could probably put in here, but after doing this,
and I'm sure if you have, um, more content like,
oh yeah, like right here, this is good.
Any FAQs you want to give the AI as much information
as possible so it has stuff to pull from.
Mm-Hmm. And yeah, these are great.
Perfect. So let's keep going.
Why should I become an authorized dealer's pretty, uh,
pretty interesting niche.
Um, how'd you come up with this?
Or why did, yeah, why, why this direction?
Well, I'm, you know, I'm, I have a,
a small equity stake in it,
but really just kinda the, you know, the creative, the,
the marketing sort of guy on it.
So I'm very, very much was approached by a friend
who found out my digital core stuff
and then partnered with their team to kind
of take, take it to the market.
Awesome. Awesome. All right. So here's what I'm gonna do.
I don't know if you have any testimonials right now,
but I'm just gonna save it as is.
Mm-Hmm. All right.
So now we've got selling solar, selling sunset over here.
I'm gonna click on that. I'm gonna click on Create new,
I'm sorry, not create New Next Step.
Has anybody else heard of, uh, vsl AI in here?
Shannon or Amy? Let me know in the comments.
Um, so right, as you can see right now,
it's literally creating a customer map
for your particular offer and business.
And I think this is, let me know if this is like on point.
So, selling solar,
launching a thriving solar bit sales business, aspire,
like the demographics, aspiring solar sales professionals,
general contractors, Mm-Hmm.
Owners of roofing businesses, HVAC salespeople,
anyone interested in starting
or growing a solar sales business. Is that correct?
Yeah, exactly. All right.
So what I love about this app is how that,
how it breaks down each, I each like customer
pain point and benefit.
And these are all like the building blocks you need
to basically create your ads from.
So this becomes almost like your
offer Bible, in my opinion.
And I believe every single business or product
or service that you like, start to create ads from Mm-hmm,
needs to have this step-by-step like analysis.
Um, so you aren't running in the dark, right?
Because if you don't have this stuff listed out, like
verbatim and very clearly, then you,
you almost don't have like this place,
you don't have a reference point.
So this is, this is your foundation.
Um, what is your core pain point?
Lack of comprehensive industry specific sales training
and resources for launching
and growing successful solar sales business.
Is that right? Is that what Yeah, this is
Are missing. Yeah, I mean, this
is all on point.
I guess I, you know, doing this manually,
this is like awesome to see it.
I'll, I'll, I'll let you keep going.
I have a couple questions on it, but
Absolutely. I'm just reading it
so I understand it.
Yeah, no, no, totally.
But, so this for me is like bite-size.
Like, I don't have to go search on Google, I don't have
to go watch YouTube videos, I don't
have to do all this crazy stuff.
Especially if you're like an agency
and you're, you're handling multiple clients
and multiple verticals
and all the, it's like that,
that process can get really daunting. Right?
Well, so that, that was gonna cover my question.
Do you, do you find this most useful if you're,
or I guess how, if you engaging with a, if you are engaging
with a client and they haven't done this, um,
if they have website copy like you just showed
to generate it, awesome.
If not, do you like ask, Hey, like, let's say it's pre,
let's say you're really early in the process.
Do you sort of just ask them to produce as much as they can
and then, and then you kinda like come back to them
with this to say, Hey, I think this is where we're at to,
to continually build off.
Like, I guess my ultimate question, sorry, is what stage
of the process are you using this tool?
Or is it just like, step any ear early
and as often as you can get to it,
All you need is enough information
for the AI to spit something out.
And so, you know, if the business is still in like,
concept form, yeah, I would, I would go on a Google doc
and be like, okay, who is the customer?
What is the offer? What is the problem?
Like, just do a massive brain dump.
At least you can have the text on on paper.
Yeah. And then you can dump
that into, into this program.
So you don't need a full, full offer
in order to make this happen.
That's the best thing about this.
It's like you can literally make something up
and I'm sure it would spit something out.
Um, yeah, chance says this is like a day
of research done for you in five minutes.
I know. It's f*****g amazing.
Um, and, uh, shout out
to Peter Kel for putting this together.
Um, but anyways, so as we go through this, right,
this is basically gonna be your marketing messages, right?
You got the emotional pain, feeling overwhelmed, unsure how
to navigate their solar sales industry, da da da.
So what I would do, and I'm gonna save this for you, bud,
because, uh, I'll just drop this, I'll save this
and then send it to you so you can have it as reference.
Um, so this does cost credits.
So I have you based off of like psl.ai,
you have a certain amount of credits every month.
So, um, creating a script will
basically cost you one credit.
Um, so the best part about this, right?
So next I'm gonna go to the left hand column.
And this is the best part.
He breaks down all these top VSLs
that are been, been proven in the space.
And this one made 17 million.
This one made 18 million, this one made 10 million.
Just insane amount of like success in in these.
So if I pick one
and I'm just gonna pick one, maybe like I'm me, see
shocking breakthrough, dirty secrets.
Did you know this crazy piece of info for every one
of these problems for feeling these
pain points, try this product.
Um, this is for supplements.
Let's find one maybe for SaaS,
e-comm dental supplements, women's health Biz Opportunity.
Here we go. Did you recent? Okay, LA Yeah, let's try this.
This biz opportunity 1 43 milli.
All right, so now that I have that,
I wanna create my first draft.
Okay? And it's going to spit out a script for me.
Um, this is, this is like the best part.
So I am, so are you struggling to launch
or grow your solar sales business?
Uh, look at this thriving solar business generating over
1 million in system sales.
If you're looking to master the art of solar sales
and build a successful business, I want you to imagine being
the go-to provider in your area, closing deals
with ease, da, da da.
So the best part about this, right?
It, it's like it'll spit something out for you.
This, it's not, it might not be perfect,
but yeah, it's, it's, it's taking the data
that you put in and then spitting it out.
Um, so this becomes a first draft,
but you can also go in here
and be like, okay, I want a different one.
Let me actually just save this one for you.
Um, because these are all, these all cost me,
cost me credit, but that's okay.
Um, well, thank you, dude. It's all good.
I I, I wanted to do a, um, a tutorial on this anyways,
because like, yeah, I just wanted
to show people how valuable it is.
'cause I've been testing it myself
and I've just been finding a ton of like, success with it.
So, um, here's another one.
Um, and, and I'll share with you like another hack that I do
to make these stand out even more,
but what's the difference between generic sales training
and industry specific solar sales training?
There you go. That seems a little bit more on point.
Yeah, that I do like that. That's cool.
Yeah. Well, generic sales training provides a broad
strategies applicable to any industry, da, da, da, you know,
I would, because it kind of spits out in a,
like a robotic way.
I would go in here and probably like, casualized,
that's not a word, but like, make it sound more casual. Is
This honestly your process?
Like, did, you're like,
I know you're probably really good at scripting in general.
Like, so would, but it, you, are you actually using this
and then you like, like, like in anything easier
to edit than it is to sort of like crave from scratch?
Absolutely, man. Um, yeah, in my agency I've adopted this,
um, this procedure, uh, not for everything, like, for like,
if I'm doing certain like UGC style ads, blah, blah, blah,
like very simple stuff.
Yeah. But for VSLs in particular, which is something
that you probably will, will be creating
because it VSLs are more of a longer cell.
Yeah. Um, then yeah,
this is def definitely something worth using.
Uh, so let me just save this
and you can, I'll share it with you.
But the next process that I do after,
after this is you can do crazy stuff like this
where, let's say I want to get a bunch of headline hooks.
I can just go here to VSL leads.
I haven't even tested all these,
but, um, oh, hooks and headlines right here.
From here, I want to go to 25 VSL hooks.
And, and this is gonna be like all of your
testing variations.
Let's say you, you find AVSL that you like, you modify it,
and then you're gonna create hooks for that.
What it does is it breaks it down into like these
four categories.
Mm-Hmm. Best case scenario, fascination plus,
amazing benefit breaking news.
My amazing miracle headlines
and their amazing miracle headlines.
Like this to me is, is just like so f*****g fast.
Yeah, for sure.
Like, I, I could do this, but like, do I wanna do it?
Not really. Um, so anyways, this gives you, like,
gives some options, um,
because these all potentially could be their own ad
variation that you can test, um, right.
Same video, just a different headline.
Provide you wildly different results.
Um, so from this process, basically
what I do is I'll start to script it out.
So I'll put that script in, into, um, a Google doc similar
to this, and then I'll just basically write the,
put the scripts out and then match AB roll shot.
But let's say it's probably in your position,
you're probably just gonna be a
talking head most of the time.
Yep. Um, and so you really just need b-roll stock
animations, that kind of stuff to, to really fill the video.
Um, sorry, my kid is crying in the background,
but that's basically the whole process.
And then once you shoot, obviously that's,
that's a whole nother set of things,
but you know, the editing becomes really easy
because you've done all the,
the heavy lifting in the beginning.
Yeah, this is awesome. I mean, like I said,
I'm put together a, I actually shared that one ad that I
with you a while back,
but yeah, to scale the process, um,
is kind of where I'm at now.
It's like, all right, that took, so back, back to, back
to being an ad guy or attempting it.
Definitely. So I wanna share one thing too
with everybody is, um, I'm gonna,
I'm working on a training right now, uh, that
I'll share soon, but it's basically
advanced ad creative testing.
So I'll go through this really quick,
but I'll do a more comprehensive video.
Um, so like the whole thing is measure
what gets measured gets improved, right?
It's like if you're trying to lose weight
and you're not like checking like check,
you're not checking your weight
or you're not counting your calories,
you're just kind of like doing whatever.
You're not gonna actually see progress week after week.
Uh, and the same thing applies to ads.
So most people, when they go
and test ads, they'll be like, okay, random idea number one,
random idea number two, random idea number three, right?
It's like this part as a creative, it's like, seems fun.
It's like, oh, let's make like a funny skit.
Or, oh, I had this one idea to create an ad, da da da.
I used to make ads like that
where it would be like, oh, this would be cool.
Um, and sometimes they work, but most of the time they don't
because you're, you're not basing it off of real avatars
and real, I would say, pain points.
And so that's not a good way to do it.
It's kind of like this spraying prey method where, uh,
you know, you're just kind of like throwing spaghetti at
the wall and seeing what sticks.
So it really comes down to clear messaging,
having the right angles and targeting.
And that's basically what we sh
what we went over in the vsl.ai process
is getting clear on your messaging cl
getting clear on your angles.
Um, so, you know,
especially if it's your first time running ads like this,
if you don't do this process, you are going to waste time
and you're gonna waste money, like without a doubt.
And so this is really the shortcut to avoiding that process.
And, um, have you guys heard of like the scientific method,
uh, where you kind of, like, you put something out,
you observe it, and then you analyze it
and then you kind of repeat, repeat that process?
Um, this is kind of like that,
but what I've come up with is
what I call like the AAA method, which is your angle,
your ad type, and the action, which action
for me just stands for offer.
Um, it just sounds cool when you have three
a's it's just easy to remember.
Uh, but so we basically just went through the avatar, right?
By doing the VSL ai, we came up with the avatar, which was,
uh, it's somewhere in here.
Yeah. The people who have HVAC companies are already
doing that kind of stuff, right?
The demographic right here, this is our avatar.
Um, let's go back core pain point, right?
We've got lack of comprehensive industry specific sales
training and resources for launching.
So essentially that becomes the, excuse me,
that becomes the messaging that we wanna focus on next.
We want to, once we know that, then we want
to decide which ad type we want to create.
Um, this, this makes VSLs,
but you can still make an ad
that's like UGC style.
So it's just like you on your phone
and you can read that ad, you know, very,
very authentically, like
with very little editing in my opinion,
where you're just like, you know, filming yourself, Hey,
you guys struggling to launch your own or launch
and grow your own solar sales business.
Check this out if you want, you know what I mean?
Just like keep it really casual
or you can have it very professional commercial
where you're like talking to camera
and there's good lighting, right?
Each one will have a different effect.
Um, and it's definitely worth testing both formats.
So lastly, you have your action, I think you mentioned,
I forget what it was, but, um, anyways, you know that,
you know, you, you know your offer,
but that comes in at the end of the video.
So when you fill that out, it'll look something like this.
This is another example of a different company that I, uh,
created ads for,
but in this example, it's like women who are, this,
this product is for leakproof panties.
Sorry, just to give you guys context.
I did touch upon this in the, in the previous training.
So, um, ad type UGC story,
their biggest pain point is spending thousands
of dollars on pads and diapers.
And the offer is buy one, get one free, basically.
So once you've dialed in that now it's time
to put your hooks and headlines into place.
The key to testing accurately is measuring one single
variation at a time.
Lemme say that again. One single variation at a time.
I know a lot of people will,
and I know when people aren't testing properly is when they
have like, let's say five
or 10 ads on the Facebook ad library.
And let me just type in like, um, real estate
and it looks okay, this is a really bad example
'cause it's all like, but yeah, that,
that would probably be, lemme just go
back, follow this one.
Okay. Yeah. So this is, this is kind of a bad example,
but regardless, if I knew someone was testing
the proper way, they would have slight variations
to each one of these ads.
Um, and basically like,
let's say the text would be different
or the hook would be different.
Um, so this, for example,
like they have just one video like this,
but if they're truly testing this properly,
they would have maybe a headline up here
and they would have like five different variations
of this headline of the same video,
but like five different headlines.
Does that make sense? Mm-Hmm.
Um, so going back to that,
it looks something like this from a tree map perspective.
So let's say you were to go with this ad
right here.
Are you struggling to launch
or grow your solar sales business?
Okay, so let's say you shot this whole thing,
and let's say you shot at UGC style on your phone.
Very amateur, you're just talking to camera, right?
So that would be, that would be your base ad.
And what I mean by base, it's like that doesn't change,
the messaging doesn't change there.
Now when you're testing these ads, you're going to add
a variable here, which is your text overlay.
And that's gonna look like your ad plus one
of those headlines that says, where is that?
On the very bottom Discover
how Jane doe's Journey became a solar sales pro, right?
Is that making sense? Mm-Hmm.
So you have this headline plus your base ad that becomes
one variation or actually one angle, so to speak.
Um, and then below that, if you wanted
to add more variations, you can have a visual hook
in there to match the angle.
So let's say you have
this discover Jane doe's journey
to becoming a solar sales pro.
Let's say you broke down, like you shot like three separate,
um, visual hooks or four separate visual hooks for this.
Maybe you show, and these could be like stock footage too,
but like person installing solar panels,
that could be like one visual hook, right?
Um, maybe you can show, show solar sales,
like screenshots of like how much money they're making. Um,
And, and this kind of is your process for, you know,
just sort of the, the opening visual is just sort of come up
with a bunch and then, and then test the ones you think are
like, like your top choices.
Yeah. Uh, pretty much.
So like, I don't know the industry that well, so it's hard
for me to come up with these potential angles.
But let's say this, this angle is talking just to like,
um, just to i's say called uh, contractors, right?
So the avatar is contractors who want to add this
to their business, right?
That's, that would be avatar angle number one.
Avatar angle number two would be maybe people
who just wanna start their own solar business from the get
go, maybe have no experience, right?
So you, you gotta put them in buckets.
So the message is very defined to the person,
and then you want to make visual hooks that match
the messaging, if that makes sense.
Yep. Okay. Fantastic.
So I'll give you a little bit of a insight of
what this looks like for this particular product.
Um, we had one headline, all right?
And the headline was Budget
Conscious Solution for incontinence.
And for anybody who doesn't know what incontinence is,
is basically, uh, women who pee their pants, like,
who don't have control over their bladder, happens like
after birth, you know, at a certain age.
Um, but what we found after just testing ads
and doing like customer feedback, we found that like
what people really cared about, um, was the price.
Like, and, and so what we wanted to test was
how effective is it to lead with
budget conscious types of headlines or savings headlines?
Because we were leading with like headlines like, oh,
like no more embarrassing leaks in public, right?
So that's a completely different pain point.
Um, the pain point is embarrassment,
but the pain point here is, look, I don't have enough money.
Like I can't afford it. So we intentionally split test this.
Um, and then we added five visual hooks that kind
of correspond with this
cost saving, uh, hook.
So it looks something like this.
So I've grouped this main headline,
and then from here
it's H 33 6.
You can see here that, let me just,
oops, let me share
Budget conscious solution for incontinence.
A few months back I discovered I had incontinence when I
leaked in public for the first time.
But it wasn't until I found these leak-proof panties
that it changed everything.
All right? So I'm not gonna play the whole video,
but, um, this was the hook.
So right budget conscious, budget conscious solution
for incontinence that remains the constant variable.
Um, or the constant headline
and then the visual just changes.
So this is the base ad from three seconds onward.
That doesn't change. Mm-Hmm.
Um, this is hook variation number two,
Budget conscious solution for incontinence,
Just throwing panties out. Budget
Conscious Variation. Number three,
Budget conscious solution for incontinence.
Just showing Budget con
Money stacking and just solution diaper stacking
And for incontinence.
Number four, Budget
conscious solution for incontinence.
Stop motion of of things,
dollar bills going inside of that.
And this is like a random one
Budget conscious solution for incontinence.
A few months,
Found this product on Amazon
and just had like, peed on the screen.
Um, so is that making sense, brother?
Oh yeah. Okay, cool.
I think this is, this is one of those things that, you know,
it, you just, you just gotta do it,
but you gotta kind of think in that very systematic way,
um, that way it's like step by step.
'cause if you jump into it, you're like, oh,
like I gotta be this, all this stuff.
And it's like, no, just take it one step at a time.
Okay, I got my avatar, I got my angles.
All right, next I gotta just figure out which type
of ad I want to create UGC vs L commercial,
and then I gotta shoot it
and then I gotta make my variations.
That's really what comes out
When you're, when you would you rec.
Okay, so like even the, the first decision of sort of like,
in our case, it'd be for these probably talking HeadStyle
for sure, which maybe is less,
but like, okay, so are you trying to limit
what you're testing and not kind of come out the gate with
like one version of UGC?
And then having that, obviously with all
of its different headline hooks, sort of, uh,
visual testings at the same time you're running like, okay,
then we're also gonna run a vs.
Like, are you trying to really,
I mean obviously I know we're trying to limit
what you're testing against each other to get actual data,
but how do you recommend, is it,
would you recommend doing like one of both styles
and even obviously within that having variations
to test those against each other?
But
Yeah, how would Absolutely.
Um, because in the testing phase, you don't need
to spend a lot of money to
know if something's working or not.
Um, and, and it's just a matter of how you organize the,
the ads within Facebook.
Yeah. So it's like, and nowadays ai, I'm sorry.
Yeah, AI is so good
that you really just need to target broad.
Um, so you don't need to mess.
I mean, you could probably do like interest testing,
like maybe some real estate keywords that you'd know about,
but broad testing is really like effective these days.
Um, so that eliminates one extra
variable that you need to focus on.
So it's like, okay, I'm gonna target men between the ages
of 30 and 70 or whatever, right?
So, and then in the ad group I'm going to put just,
you know, the one angle and then the five variations.
That's just gonna be one thing with its own separate budget.
And basically from there, I'm trying to see which one out
of those five are going to resonate the most
with the, with the customer.
Um, and then you can have different ad sets
depending on different angles and ad types.
So you want to just like, you wanna in, uh, you don't want
to group and mix different ad creatives
and different ad messaging together into one ad set.
Mm-Hmm. Because then you don't really know
what is working and like yes,
what message is getting across.
So yeah, you can, you can test however many you want.
Um, just make sure that you're,
you're doing it in an organized way and it's intentional.
Awesome. Yeah, I'm excited.
I'm, I, I guess I'm, I, uh, been a little intimidated by it.
Um, and then even like jumping into, I forget you sent me,
I think it was at 3 2, 1 training by,
I think that's what he called it.
And I'm blanking on his name.
I haven't seen his videos in a while on the YouTube,
uh, what was his name? I'm gonna pull it up. Um,
Oh, the, um, was it the dynamic
creative testing guy or no?
Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
I, uh, that's, that's one of the methods.
Um, if you just look up dynamic creative testing in
on YouTube, yeah, you'll find, you'll find a ton
of stuff like this is Facebook has become much easier.
It's this guy right here, Nick Riet. Exactly. Yeah.
Yeah, dude, this, this guy breaks it
down, it's here somewhere.
But if you start running your ads,
like, just copy this
and you'll, I, I guarantee you'll find,
I can't think right now, dynamic creative.
So basically dynamic creative testing is, um,
it's Facebook Facebook's way of like finding the winners
for you, which is super, super valuable.
So here it is right now. So I'll share this right now in the
link in the Zoom.
Um, and it makes creative much easier to do
in my opinion, because I think you just focus on
like doing creative.
Not so much like hardcore media buying
because like the media buying stuff, there used to be,
there's like a lot of like tactics and stuff,
but ultimately if you have a winning message
and a winning ad, like you don't have to do that much with,
with the ads like the Facebook ads themselves.
Like it'll take care of itself.
So if you can find
good metrics from the early on, like let's say you have a,
a click-through rate of like two to 3%
or like 1.1 0.5, like anything over,
like one is good on Facebook, but,
but like really good ads are like in the 3% area.
And let's say your cost per click is like a dollar
or less than a dollar, basically that's telling you
that your ad is resonating
with the audience. Does that make sense?
Mm-Hmm. The cheaper your Facebook ads are
means your ad is really good.
So it wants to give it to more people so
you'll know if your ads are costing you a s**t ton of money,
it's not a good ad because, and,
and no matter what people say, oh, Facebook ads are
so expensive, da da da, it's because their ad suck
and they don't know how to properly like
talk to their customers.
Um, and it doesn't matter about like cost of CPMs
and all this stuff, if you have a really amazing ad,
it's gonna be really cheap.
Um, so anyways, that's gonna be an indicator for you, okay.
Once you start analyzing the ads that come in, okay, this,
this message is working.
Okay, great, well is there any ways
that we can improve or expand on this?
Maybe improve it even further.
Like why don't we try 10 more hooks,
but focusing specifically on this type of message
and creating variations of this message.
And then maybe let's shoot some like more wild out,
you know, kind of crazy stuff out there to,
to make it even more engaging.
Um, Chad, do you know
where I can find affiliate product to sell?
I'm trying to find something that is online product
that could be so, well you can sell vsl.ai.
Um, I'm an affiliate for it, so Yeah, you can,
here, I'll drop the link.
I think it's, I was gonna do some stuff for it,
but yeah, in terms of, uh, promoting it,
'cause it's just like such a valuable tool,
but yeah, you can, you can sign up there, Chan.
Um, so yeah, Ryan, when you get through that process,
you can just hit me up and then let me,
Yeah, I'm excited, man. Like
I said, I, I, I was wearing a lot of hats
and I'm now come full circle with two products
that are essentially ready to sell other
than, you know, the ad process.
So I'm kind of back to
where I originally met you at in, in the stage.
And so we'll see.
Um, there they are saturated areas
and so like, not, I obviously recognize that,
but I think the solar one might be a little more unique in
terms of what it, what the offer ultimately is.
So I really, I trust my instincts on the ad stuff,
but also like, smart enough to be overwhelmed.
Like, dang, there's a lot of, like, I love that it's a mix
of an like, analytics, like art and science.
So that's where I'm like, dude, let's go.
Let's, I want to crack both
100%, man.
It's gotta be, especially if you're handling all the parts,
you're gonna have to deal with both.
'cause a lot of editors will only deal
with the creative side.
Um, and that's why I think, you know, this course,
even if they're not doing it, they're aware of it.
Um, but the data's really gonna tell you everything.
Um, and I, and you can learn very fast from the data.
Um, and it's like, if it's not working from the beginning,
don't keep spending money on it.
Yeah. You, You can't make a bad ad get better
by adding more money to it.
That's like, uh, that's like a $30,000 lesson for me. Yeah.
Which I've, I've figured out myself.
Um, so if it, if it,
if it starts performing right out the gate, like
it, it's a great sign.
If it's not, then you still got,
you gotta go back and fix the ad.
Aren't saturated niches good though?
'cause there's enough info out there that you can, uh, copy
and paste basically.
Copy and paste. I mean, if it's, if it's,
if it's competitive, then yeah, there's like a s**t ton
of money to be made in there.
Um, what's his name?
Peter Kel, the one who, who designed this app.
He, he has like the best performing VSL in the
world, um, on YouTube.
And so when he says, like, when he, he only goes into niches
that are crazy saturated
because it means, you know, then there's a lot
of competition and there's, the stakes are higher,
but then the, the revenue opportunities weigh higher
too. So that,
That, that is a kind of a good question though, as far
as like, how,
how does the approach differ when you're in a space
that's sort of like new and you're trying to pioneer
versus like, Hey, this is super saturated,
but this means we have to kind of pivot
how we, how we approach it?
Both, both can be one with the right sort of angle.
Yeah, well, I think it's, you know,
everything we spoke about in terms of like avatar research,
pain point, stuff that is like one component of it.
The second would be competitor research.
So really studying what other YouTube ads are doing,
studying what other Facebook ads are doing, like seeing
how they're positioning themselves
and be like, okay, let's, let's take some of that
and then let's, let's do something they're not doing.
Um, and that's how you're gonna stand out
is finding those little gaps in a competitive market,
finding a very unique angle that hasn't been spoken about
that people are gonna be curious about.
Um, so in the,
let's say the affiliate world, um, people
who are selling products on ClickBank,
are you familiar with ClickBank?
Yeah, I try to get set up on there,
but it's sort of, it doesn't, it's, I couldn't get to kind
of integrate with Kajabi, which is
where the digital courses are,
but I think they now have a new integration.
I just saw that makes it a little, you could basically po
host on both, but yes, familiar with it and,
and very much eager to sort of take advantage of it.
Yeah. Um, I've, I've sold a couple products on ClickBank,
um, but the,
and I've taken some courses on how to basically like
tackle some of these really competitive niches like fat loss
and like dental
and um, like spirituality.
Like there's, you know,
there's some really hard hitters in there.
Um, and so what I've learned is it, it really comes down
to the angle that you, that you're putting out.
So for example, there is this one, uh,
teeth cleaner product.
It's called Dent Doc,
and it's on, it's like, it's on ClickBank,
but it was the, the angle that had worked really well
for them was like, weird solution cleans your teeth in,
in minutes without brushing your teeth
or something, something weird like that.
You know, it's this weird angle that like, you don't know
what it is, but there's like curiosity, um, involved.
And they basically tested that and it worked.
And then when it started to die out,
then they just created a completely new angle.
They tested a bunch of angles, obviously,
but they found a new angle
and then they ran that for a few more months and scaled it.
So in any business, I really believe
that once you do find an angle that works,
then it's off to the races.
This could be for any platform, Facebook, YouTube, TikTok,
and it could be for any type of vertical.
It could be any type of video ad
because at the end of the day you're talking
to a human being on the other side of the screen, right?
And, um, it doesn't matter what format it's in, it's like,
can you get this message across?
Can you keep their attention, keep their curiosity?
Um, so yeah, once you get that,
it's really about dialing in your funnel afterwards.
So conversion rate, optimization, that kind of stuff.
So that comes after the click,
but getting your ad to work,
I think is probably the hardest part.
Welcome, uh, studio, sho Studio.
I think that's how you pronounce it.
Um, does anybody have any other questions for me?
Oh yeah, sio. Yeah, I know you guys, of course, um, studio,
they, they do similar stuff to my e-com, uh, e-commerce,
they per, they do custom ad creative too,
so it's good to see you in here, bud.
Um, yeah. Any other questions for me guys?
I think this is a really, like,
went really deep on stuff on this
call. Do you share
Some of the templates you use? I
know it pretty just basic Google Sheet kind of
template stuff, but, uh, within ads creative, I know, like
what coming back, what, how would you kind of sell how
to use UIN in this process versus like the trainings,
the whatever templates, like someone that's kind of new-ish
to the ad space, but a lot of video editing stuff and,
and website copy building like
gr step one is just make our own stuff to how mu how mu
how much of the templatized stuff that you kind
of share can we leverage from, from the ads orx stuff?
Oh, I mean, a lot of it really, you know,
'cause like our, the, our templates come at the end, right?
It's like, it's like the finishing touch.
It's like the polishing of the ads.
So, um, you know, you can use as many as you, you
as you'd like really as long as um, hi Ellie, as long really
as, as if you've got the hooks
and the angle's down, then slap on, you know, slap on grids,
use, um, the call to action buttons, use
the captions use, you know, there's so many opportunities
to just make the video more visually appealing.
I think that's where the ads are.
X templates come in is like, is really sweetening the ad,
like making it that much more engaging than just a talking
head with nothing on screen.
Templates will make, make your ads look better
and, you know, if you wanna submit any of your ads
to the group, I'm sure me
and a few other people would make some suggestions on like,
okay, maybe you can do a split screen here.
You should add a guarantee seal,
or maybe you should add social proof right here.
Um, and those are all little things that you can,
you'd probably pick up on over time.
Hey, hey Ali, what's going on man? Do you have a mic?
I know they do a ton of creative.
I'd be curious to, uh, see like if there's anything you guys
are struggling with right now.
I know you guys have a big team,
Me, right? Um,
I'm just struggling like to improve and get better,
but I wanna get better quicker,
but that I can only go so fast.
I think that's everyone's, everyone's, uh, problem, right?
You know, I've been doing this stuff for like five years
and then I've been doing it, doing it five years, like day
after day after day.
And like, even for me, it took me a long time to really like
figure out, okay, from A to Z how this stuff works
and there's always room for me to get better too.
You know, I'm always trying to get more information in the
door, um, to refine what I know about marketing
and direct response.
Um, it's,
but it really comes down to knowing like, I,
like in the training, you know,
if you're just doing editing, you're just gonna know a part
of the marketing strategy.
But if you're doing copywriting,
if you're doing creative strategy,
if you're doing production editing
and deploying the ads, you're gonna get a really like
broad view of how everything works.
Um, but I think as an editor,
if you're just doing editing Jan,
like doing your own creative, uh, strategy
using the vsl.ai app
or, um, just having a strong foundation of like
what you're editing, like, you know, the customer, you know,
the app, you know, the pain points really well, um, is going
to make you a better editor
because you don't overcompensate.
And I see this a lot is like editors will overcompensate in
the, in the ad to make up for their lack of understanding
of the target demographic. Does that make sense?
Uh, so, So editors,
because you know, the, the tools that we have are like,
okay, let me add a graphic here.
Let me add b-roll shots here, let me add a zoom effect here,
let me add music, right?
Those are the lever levers that we can pull as editors.
Um, but sometimes that's not effective.
Sometimes it's like maybe pulling back, um, or doing less
or doing the right things at the right time.
Um, but when you understand the customer
and the pain point really, really well,
then you can tell a really good story.
And I think it's the storytelling
that really makes someone watch the video all the way
through, right?
If you hook 'em in, get them to stop the scroll,
hook them in, engage them, da da da,
keep that process going.
'cause you, you want to be editing as if you're like
teasing the customer all the way throughout the video.
That makes sense. Um,
and then you can layer on all of your cool effects
and stuff to make the video even that much more captivating.
Um, so yeah, I think that that's the biggest process.
And I would say even for my editors at my agency,
like they don't touch a lot of the creative strategy.
They don't do scripting, right?
So when we give them assets, we give them raws, it's like,
okay, we have the script already pre-written
and then it's up to the editor to put it together.
Um, and some of them hit it like on the dot
and some of 'em are like, yo, you're way off.
Like, what happened? It's
because they haven't done the full research themselves
to really understand who they're talking to.
Um, so I hope that makes sense.
Yeah, makes total sense. Um,
Cool man.
I mean, you're showing up, dude, you're,
you're getting better every day.
Yeah, just getting information like this, being surrounded
by other people and talking about it,
I think is like the fastest way to level up.
It's like if you're doing it alone
and you're like not sure if you're getting better
and you don't, you can't ask questions,
it's gonna take a long time to grow.
Um, but yeah, I have, okay, so studio,
I'm learning more creative concept compared
to strategy practically.
I understand all the footages creatives needed ad creative
flow, but not really on strategy, still learning.
Yeah, that's a really good like, problem to be in
because the solution is not as hard as you think.
Um, you missed it.
Ali, earlier on this call, we went over
how we determine basically the customer avatar
and the core pain points.
Um, and strategy in my opinion is really, is really just
that, um, who have I talking to?
What is the message that I want to get to them?
What are their core pain points?
And how do I develop creative that supports the, you know,
the claims that I wanna make to this person.
And there's like three
different people that I want to talk to.
I wanna have a very specific message to each one of them,
and then depending on where they're at in the funnel
as well, right?
So we can definitely go into strategy a little bit further,
uh, on another call.
But since you joined a little late,
we can't go over it right now. But
Also, um, could we like one day maybe go
through like personal branding?
Um, I'm not sure how, uh, experienced, uh,
you are in this field, but it's sometimes difficult for me
that just like to bring out, um, through my editing, like
who the person is, um, like that's talking.
So personal branding for yourself or for other people?
For other people, for someone else.
'cause like I feel like I'm always buting heads
with, um, the person.
'cause I have like my own style,
but he, he wants a different style, right?
And I, I don't like the style that he wanted it.
I just try to edit like the way I want it all the time
instead of the way he wants.
Ah, I see what you're saying.
Um, yeah, I think it's hard
to have leverage over that when there's a client paying you
for it, you know what I mean?
Uh, you know, if you're an agency, if you,
you're doing a service to someone, it's like your job is
to make them happy more.
So, um, even it sometimes you have
to override your own stuff, but you know, if it's,
I I actually do like that question.
It's something kind of similar to where I found
where I definitely was editing to, you know, my style
that was start to become clear
and I didn't notice it over time, but it then just happened.
Do you find that, like, you have your style,
but I mean, how do you not stay within your style if
that's sort of like what you've perfected?
It's sort of like if you get to someone else's style
that they're asking for, I mean, does
that just mean you have to constantly develop multiple
styles and sort of like have it on, have it available?
Um, how do you leave?
I mean, how do you quickly develop like,
or sell to someone's style that they're asking for?
If it's like, not what you've done before? I just, sorry.
Oh yeah. To just to finish my question
and state it more clearly, it almost seems like for me,
particularly to get to scalable activity,
that I would rather just put my style on display for sale.
And it's sort of like, this is what I do.
It's really good in its lane.
So either like it or you don't,
but I don't have time to sort of like, it's hard
to scale picking up new styles as I go for every new client,
even though that is the reality of the game.
Um, Jen, did you have something to add to that?
Uh, no, no, no. Uh, I thought he asked me something.
Yeah, and I think that brings up a really good point,
Ryan is like, if you're, if you're known for something,
you know, like don't deviate from that.
'cause then it's like cooking 50
dishes in the, in the kitchen.
It's like, do you want to be a hometown buffet
or do you want to be like, I just make seafood.
Like I just make the best f*****g seafood ever.
Um, and I think if you have the luxury to be able
to be like, you know, this is what I do, um,
you'll attract people who are interested in
that style, right?
But if you say, I'm just an editor, you know,
and I don't specialize in anything particular,
then you're gonna attract people who are like, okay,
well I want a corporate video.
Okay, now I want a a a reel,
now I want a direct response video ad, right?
You're gonna be jumping around to all these different styles
and it's probably gonna be really difficult.
So getting clear on what you do, you know what I mean?
It's like, dude, I create UGC ads, um, in very specific way.
People are gonna come to you
and they're not gonna question like how you do it.
Would, do you recommend someone that's sort
of just starting out but is noticing that they're kind
of like, well this is what I've got good at.
Like, is it more ideal to try
and get more styles than your belt
or like, does it just make sense to just niche down
and like, Hey, this is what I do and this is what it is.
I think it's, it's, it's, it's, it's very helpful
to learn different styles, right?
Because in the video creative industry, there's like,
there's infinite, right?
There's obviously some core ones that you can,
that you can model after.
Like for example, like her mozy, Alex, her Mozy, right?
That has become a style,
like seeing the talking head videos with the captions.
Like everyone has just now taken that style.
So that becomes something definitive
that you can say, Hey, I do this style.
Um, and then if, you know, if there's another style like,
hey, like making, making a TikTok style, um, that's,
so if you can find, if there's patterns to all of it,
but like if you have a certain style, right,
and you can, you can be like, hey,
or do you wanna leave it up to me to, to define that?
Um, you can,
but I do suggest looking, being aware of different styles
because if something's working out in the field,
it's important to pay attention to
because it's like your, your style may not be tested
and proven versus the things that are out there that are,
that's why a lot of people will be like,
I want it like Alex, her Moie,
or I, I want it just like this
because this one has a million views on it, right?
So it just comes back to like that feedback loop of, hey,
this is working and I, I want it to look like that.
Does that answer your question?
I think I rambled a little bit.
No, no, for sure. Um,
I feel like you should do some trainings on like, you know,
styles, like kind of summarize 'em with like, you know,
fast track to get in,
sort of, it'd be kind of the mechanical.
Oh yeah, definitely. New content. Awesome.
I'll definitely put that on the to-do list.
Um, but I gotta head out guys, it was a really good call.
Thank you for everyone who joined in, Ryan, who was awesome,
doing a deep dive with you and Chan, Amy, Ollie.
Thanks for being on the call.
I'll post this recording up in a couple days
and, uh, I'll see you guys in the group.
Let me know if you have any further questions.